The new morning we've finally found
やっと見つけた　新しい朝は
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
月日が邪魔をする
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
向かう先は　「次」じゃなくて
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
「過」ばかり追いかけた
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
鳴り止まない　容赦ない思い出たちは
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
許してくれそうにもない
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
そろそろかな　手探り　疲れた頬を
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
葛藤がこぼれ落ちる
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
雨は　いつか止むのでしょうか
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
ずいぶん長い間　冷たい
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
雨は　どうして僕を選ぶの
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
包まれて　いいかな
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
雨は　止むことを知らずに
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
今日も降り続くけれど
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
そっと　差し出した傘の中で
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
温もりに　寄り添いながら
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
What's the matter?
どうしたの
The soldiers outside want to start negotiating.
外のヤツらが交渉したいって
We're only sending one man! He's on his way now!
一人だ　そっちに行く
Be sure not to shoot!
いいか　撃つなよ
Hands above your head!
手を頭の上に
Do anything suspicious and we won't hesitate!
怪しい動きをしたら撃つからね
He's fine.
大丈夫よ
Let him through.
通してあげて
He's someone we can trust.
信用できる人物だわ
Second Lieutenant!!
少尉
I wonder if there's any way for me to see my husband right now...
なんとか主人に会えないでしょうか
You mustn't!
いけません
There's no telling what could happen to you.
行けば　どんな目に遭うか…
There's still a chance that the army is currently under control of the anti-Bradley faction.
いまだ軍が  反ブラッドレイ派に
掌握されている可能性は
ぬぐいきれていません
Please be patient for a little longer.
今しばらく　ご辛抱ください
I see...
そう…そうですよね
You're right.
So, you say you refuse to acknowledge Truth?
真理を認めないとな
That's exactly right!
そうさ　それに　てめぇ
You also seem to think you've won
after gathering all the human sacrifices,
人柱をそろえて勝ったつもりだろうが
but you won't have your way with us so easily!
そう簡単に使われるオレたちじゃねぇぞ
Nonsense.
益体もないことを言う
Can you stand? We're going to get out of here.
立てるかい　逃げるよ
Don't bother trying.
逃げられんよ
All of you are already inside my belly.
お前たちはすでに私の腹の中だ
What on earth is this?
なんだ　こりゃ…
Is the 'Father' guy inside of that thing?
この中にあのお方だか
父上だかがいるのか
He should be with our father by now.
今ごろマスタング大佐は父上のところだ
Though I certainly can't guarantee that he is with no physical defects.
五体満足かどうかは保障せんがね
May!
メイ
豆女
Midget!
Hey you, with all the eyes! You're immortal, aren't you?
そこの目ん玉まみれさん
不老不死なのですよね
So you're not going to deny it.
否定しませんか
Sir Alphonse, let me handle him.
アルフォンス様
あれは私がもらいます
H-Hey, you won't be able to take him on alone!
ちょっ　ちょっと
あれは一人じゃ無理だよ
いえ　私には錬丹術があります
Nope, I can use Eastern Alchemy.
I get that you'll still be able to use alchemy even after he seals it off, but...
確かに錬丹術は
錬金術が封じられても使えるけど
I'm going to need you two to take on the little homunculus.
お二人には小さい方の人造人間を
お任せします
Easier said than done...
簡単に言ってくれるなぁ
He forced the colonel to open the gate...?
強制的に大佐の扉を開けた
Then why didn't he do that to begin with?
そんな荒技使えんなら
なんで今までやらなかった
Fullmetal.
鋼の
When he dragged me into the transmutation,
私を錬成に巻き込んだとき
he said, "I didn't really want to have to use this method, but we're fairly short on time."
ヤツは
「この手は使いたくなかったがしかたない」と言った
Meaning it carries a great risk for them.
ヤツらにとって
ハイリスクってことか
Probably.
おそらく
Guess it's worth a shot.
いってみっか
All right! We can use alchemy!
よし　術は使える
He's running?!
逃げた　今まで
He used to always avoid them using his shadows!
黒い影でかわしてきたのに
We may have a chance!
いけっかもしんねぇぞ
Right!
Messing up my house again? You evil kids.
また私の家を壊してくれたな
困ったヤツらだ
Your immortality is mine!
不老不死　頂きます
You don't belong here.
お前はこの場所に必要のない人間だ
Out!
消えろ
Watch out, little girl!
ダメだ　お嬢さん
こいつはノーモーションで…
He can transmute without-
May!
メイ
Just what on blazes is going on?
一体どうなっているんだ
We still can't get in touch with headquarters.
依然として　司令部との通信は
途絶えたままです
Reporting in!
報告します
Several Ishbalans have appeared within the city!
市内各所にイシュヴァール人が出没
They've engaged in combat with the guards in-
数か所で憲兵隊と…
You-
貴様
My apologies.
失礼
We don't really have the time to explain.
説明している暇はないのでな
Forgive us.
許せ
No! No!!
嫌っ　嫌
Help me! Someone, help me!
助けて　助けて
失礼　奥さん
My apologies, lady.
We mean no harm, so please tell us...
何もしないから教えてください
This is the house located here on this map, right?
この家
この場所で間違いないですか
It's starting to get really dark.
みるみる暗くなっていく
I wonder if everyone's doing their job...
みんな　うまくやってるかな
You sure this is the right place?
ここでいいんだな
Yeah, positive.
間違いない
Great.
よし　さて
Now...
The rest is up to you, Scar.
頼んだぞ　スカー
It's nice to be face to face with death every once in a while.
こうして死に直面するというのは
いいものだな
Right now, the only thing in my mind is the fact that I'll fight to the death with you.
純粋に死ぬまで戦ってやろう
という気持ちしかわいてこん
Social status, career, origin,
地位も経歴も生まれも
race, gender, name...
人種　性別　名前…
...none of that matters.
何もいらん
Not being bound by anyone and fighting just for the sake of it.
何ものにも縛られず
誰のためにでもなく　ただ戦う
How astounding.
なんと心地よい
I've finally reached this stage.
やっとたどりついた
What's wrong?!
どうした
Is this all you've got?!
これが貴様の本気か　足りん
That's not enough!
Hardly enough!
まったくもって足りんぞ
Destroy me, nameless one!
私を壊してみせろ
名もなき人間よ
You look surprised.
信じられん…といった顔だな
I don't blame you.
そうだろう　オレが
If you were to ask me some time ago,
こんなものを使うなど…
even I wouldn't have imagined that I'd be using something like this.
少し前まで
オレ自身も想像していなかった
I had always been thinking about what I was capable of doing.
自分に何ができるかを
ずっと考えていた
And this was the conclusion I'd reached.
そして　これにたどりついた
It's the transmutation circle of reconstruction that I obtained from my brother's research documents!
我が兄の研究書から得た
再構築の錬成陣だ
You humans just continue to struggle.
どこまでもあがきよるわ　人間め
メイ
May!
くそっ
Shit!
アル　メイを助けに行け
Al, you go help May.
プライドは
What about Pride?!
オレに任せとけ  一人で十分だ
Leave him to me.
I can take him!
分かった
Roger that!
お嬢ちゃん
Little girl!
おとなしくしていろ  ホーエンハイム
You keep your mouth shut, Hohenheim.
アルフォンス様…
Sir Alphonse...
どうした　どうした
What's the matter now?
随分ぬるい攻撃じゃねぇか
Those are some weak blows!
勘違いしないでください
Don't get the wrong idea.
あなたは役目を終えるまで…
Until you perform your duty...
生かしてやるってか
You need to keep me alive, eh?!
だったら　その前に
Then I'll just kick both of your asses before that happens!
てめぇらをぶっ倒すまでだ
倒す
"Kick our asses"?
やってみてくださいよ
Do try.
君は小柄だから
Since you have a small stature, you've always been fighting against people larger than you.
自分より大きい者とばかり戦ってきた
つまり　自分より小さい者と
Thus, you have little experience fighting against those who are smaller than yourself!
戦った経験が少ない
父さん　当たったら　ごめん
I apologize beforehand if I hit you, Dad!
You little...!
てめぇ…
確かに　オレはでけぇのとばかり戦ってきた
I do admit that I've always been fighting against people who were bigger than me!
だからこそ
And that's exactly why...
チビの攻撃パターンは分かるんだよ
...I know how little guys tend to attack!
師匠
Master!
ノーモーションで錬成とは厄介だね
Transmuting with no movement? That's kind of annoying.
そろそろ時間だ
It's almost time.
遊びはここまでだ
Playtime ends here.
働いてもらうぞ　人柱諸君
Time for you all to get to work.
真っ暗だな
It's pitch dark...
早く…
Hurry...
早く錬成陣の中心へ行くんだ…
Hurry and take us to the middle of the transmutation circle...
早く　ここではダメだ
Hurry!
We can't stay here!
暴れるな
Quit throwing a fit!
私を中心へ連れていけ
Hurry up and take me to the center!
早くしろ　飲み込まれる
Hurry!
We're going to get devoured!
早く
Hurry!!
時は来た
The time has come!
お前たちはこの惑星を一つの生命体と
Have you all ever thought of this planet as one life form?
考えたことがあるか
いや　生命というよりは
Well, it would be more accurate to call it a system rather than a life form.
システムと言うべきか
お前たち人間一人の
A system that records a tremendous amount of information taken from the universe,
情報量などとは比べようもない
膨大な宇宙の情報を記憶するシステム
which is incomparable to the tiny amount that each of you humans possess.
その扉を開けたら
If one were to open that gate,
一体どれほどの力を手に入れられるか
how much power do you suppose they would gain?
考えたことがあるか
Ever thought of it?
その扉を人柱諸君を使い　今ここで開く
I'm going to open that gate here and now
using these human sacrifices!
中心はそこかい
So that's the center!
グリード
Greed!
世界の中心はオレのものだ
The center of the world belongs to me!
オレは世界を手に入れる
The world is mine!
やった
He did it.
来ると思っていたよ
I knew you'd come, Greed, my son.
我が息子　グリード
お前は私から生まれた強欲だからな
You're the avarice that was born from me.
私が欲しいものは
It's only natural that you'd want everything I'd want.
お前も欲しいものなぁ
エド
Ed!
世界の中心はここだ
The true center of the world...
...is right here!
くっそ
Damn you...!
なっ　なんだ
W-What's going on?!
これは
This is...!
そうだ
That's right, allow the gates to fight each other!
扉同士　戦え　反発し合え
Repel one another!
すばらしいエネルギーだ
What an immense amount of energy!
この私が抑えるだけで
I'm almost unable to hold it down by myself.
精一杯ではないか
この力をもってして
And with this power, I shall open the gate of the planet!
この惑星の扉を開ける
何これ
What on earth?!
ウィン…リィ…
Win...ry...
何…これ…
What's... going on...?
Miss Pinako, what's...
ピナコさん　これは…
ホーエンハイム…戻ったら
Hohenheim... I'm going to punch you...
殴ってやる…
...when you come back...
エド…エ…ド…
Ed...
E... d...
God!!
神よ
我が魂に応えよ
Respond to my soul!
来い
Come!
そうだ　来い
That's right, come!
もう貴様に縛られ続ける私ではない
I shall no longer be chained down by You!
地に引きずり下ろし
I shall drag You down to earth and make You a part of me!
我が身の一部にしてくれよう
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
次回　鋼の錬金術師
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
Bow before him, humans, if he is who you call a god.
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第６１話　『神を呑みこみし者』
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
But if you do not acknowledge him so, fight!
神は
寄る辺なき人のつくりしもの
Stake thy pride.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 61, He Who Would Swallow God.
"God" is an invention of those with nobody else to turn to.